Serhii Misiura

Senior full-stack engineer

■ maradox49s@gmail.com
■ TX, USA
□ Github

Profile

A passionate full-stack engineer with over ten years of professional experience developing software for web environments. I quickly help startups and enterprises with prototypes and ideas by efficiently building those things into reality. I specialize in JavaScript and TypeScript frameworks including React, Next and Node as well as cloud services including AWS and Azure.

I've been working as a founding engineer and a lead developer in various agile teams and I aim to apply my background and skills to develop products that are well-crafted and thoughtfully designed.

Professional Experience

Web tech lead, JOOR ☑

JOOR is a data analytics company that connects brands and retailers globally to deliver seamless digital wholesale management from connection to payment.

01/2022 - 11/2022 Fishers, IN, USA, USA

- Prepared a 37 pages-long PIA report document based on the business model.
- Conducted backlog grooming sessions and handled writing business requirements and technical assumptions
- Released a dashboard app from scratch in React in three months with features like multi-tenancy and different entities
- Built an admin app from scratch in React in six weeks with business processes like tenant management, user management, entity management etc
- Set up the environments for whole development life-cycle by hosting production/staging/dev environments with UAT (user acceptance testing) ability and dockerization
- Spearheaded the JOORPay implementation, which brands can accept multiple forms of payment across 135 currencies and receive payments quickly while qualified retailers benefit from 60-day net terms

Senior front-end engineer, *Ideamarkets, Lab* □

Ideamarket Is a Literal Marketplace for Ideas (and Online Reputation). The goal is to relieve social media platforms of the task of making judgments on behalf of the public.

- Built reusable React custom hooks for interacting with blockchain data to integrate 15+ smart contracts deployed on Arbitrum
- Boosted the performance of the blog app by leveraging JAM stack with Wordpress headless CMS and Gatsby
- Restructured GraphQL API for improved maintainability and security.
- Introduced and applied lots of improvements including virtualization, lazyloading and SSR
- Overhauled the React dashboard app and introduced several layers of abstractions for services, views and models to reduce duplicate code
- Built a UI component library using storybook and ant design which significantly boosted the team velocity and consistency

Senior full-stack lead, *Fairfly* □

FairFly's corporate travel management insights are an end-to-end solution for a data-driven travel program.

• Documented all concerns and incidents in Github, Jira

11/2020 - 01/2022

USA

02/2018 - 11/2020

Tel Aviv, Israel

- Handled communication between PMs and Designer
- Designed and implemented the product including DevOps targeting millions of users, introduced several layers of abstractions, emphasizing reusability and scalability
- Implemented and managed the Design System library

Founding full-stack engineer, *Starstock* □

StarStock is a nationwide, one stop shop for licensees to order drink and food online

08/2016 – 02/2018 London, UK

- Made an ecommerce storefront and admin application for retailers and brand owners
- Built a common component library as a Github submodule which boosted the performance and productivity of the team more than double
- Translated hundreds of pages from Figma design into React components using a component library for the consistency
- Integrated several payment providers including sagepay and stripe

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Illinois State University

03/2012 – 04/2016 Normal, Illinois, USA

Skills

JavaScript / TypeScript	• • • •	React / Next / Redux	• • • • •
react-query / apollo-graphql	• • • •	Node / Remix / Express	• • • • •
PostgreSQL / MySQL / MongoDB	• • • •	AWS / Docker / Kubernetes	• • • • •

Organizations

Doodles Academy, Web Developer

Doodles Academy is a nonprofit organization and it's committed to providing educational resources under OER. I am volunteering in JS/TS/React/GraphQL subjects to provide best practices and design patterns.

06/2018 – present Portland, Oregon, USA, USA

Interests

• Climbing • Soccer • Hiking